[{"question":"A carbohydrate splitting enzyme is secreted by:","a":"Liver","b":"Zymogen cells of gastric glands","c":"Salivary glands","d":"Crypts of Lieberkuhn","hint":"","correct":"c"},{"question":"In which part of gut, proteins ultimately degraded to amino acids?","a":"Small intestine","b":"Colon","c":"Stomach","d":"Caccum","hint":"","correct":"a"},{"question":"Vermiform appendix is made up of:","a":"Digestive tissue","b":"Respiratory tissue","c":"Excretory tissue","d":"Lymphatic tissue","hint":"","correct":"d"},{"question":"Pancreatic juice takes part in digestion of:","a":"Proteins and carbohydrates","b":"Proteins, fats and carbohydrates","c":"Proteins and fats","d":"Proteins only","hint":"","correct":"b"},{"question":"Which group contains biocatalysts?","a":"Peptidase, amylase, rennin","b":"Myosin, oxytocin, adrenaline","c":"Rhodopsin, pepsin, steapsin","d":"Glucose, amino acids, fatty acids","hint":"","correct":"a"},{"question":"Duct leading from parotid gland and opening into vestibule is:","a":"Wharton's duct","b":"Stensen's duct","c":"Wolffian duct","d":"Infra-orbital","hint":"","correct":"b"},{"question":"Man cannot digest cellulose, whereas Cow and other herbivorous animals can because: ","a":"they have stomach enzyme cellulase in their","b":"they masticate it well by chewing teeth.","c":"they have bacteria in their alimentary canal which digest cellulose.","d":"none of the above","hint":"","correct":"c"},{"question":"Pancreatic lipase acts upon:","a":"Glycogen","b":"Triglycerides","c":"Disaccharides","d":"Polypeptides","hint":"","correct":"b"},{"question":"DNase and RNase are enzymes secreted by:","a":"Pancreas","b":"Stomach","c":"Gall bladder","d":"Intestine","hint":"","correct":"a"},{"question":"Teeth of adult man, not present in milk dentition are:","a":"Molars","b":"Premolars","c":"Canines","d":"Incisors","hint":"","correct":"b"},{"question":"Diastema is a toothless gap in the jaws of rabbit between:","a":"Premolars and molars","b":"Incisors and molars","c":"Canines and molars","d":"Incisors and premolars","hint":"","correct":"d"},{"question":"Which of the following are reabsorbed in the alimentary canal as such?","a":"Albumen of egg","b":"Polysaccharides","c":"Proteins","d":"Fat soluble vitamins","hint":"","correct":"d"},{"question":"The pH of succus entericus is:","a":"7.6","b":"6.6","c":"5.6","d":"2.0","hint":"","correct":"a"},{"question":"Mammalian teeth are:","a":"Acrodont","b":"Homodont","c":"Thecodont","d":"Polyphyodont","hint":"","correct":"c"},{"question":"Which of the following control the amount of enzymes in pancreatic juice?","a":"Cholecystokinin","b":"Secretin","c":"Pancreozymin","d":"Gastrin","hint":"","correct":"c"},{"question":"Rennin acts on milk protein and changes:","a":"Caseinogen into casein","b":"Casein into paracasein","c":"Paracasein into cascinogen","d":"Caseinogen into paracasein","hint":"","correct":"b"},{"question":"Gall bladder is attached to liver in the region of:","a":"Quadrate lobe","b":"Caudate lobe","c":"Right lobe","d":"Left lobe","hint":"","correct":"c"},{"question":"If pH of stomach is made 7, which component 66. of food would be affected?","a":"Starch","b":"Protein","c":"Fat","d":"Sucrose","hint":"","correct":"b"},{"question":"If the chyme of a person who had orally consumed only starch as food is analysed before it enters the duodenum, it will show the presence of:","a":"Maltose and glucose","b":"Dextrin and maltose","c":"Starch, dextrin and maltose","d":"Starch, dextrin and glucose","hint":"","correct":"c"},{"question":"Sodium taurocholate aids in:","a":"Absorption","b":"Defecation","c":"Assimilation","d":"Emulsification","hint":"","correct":"d"},{"question":"How many teeth in human, erupt only once in the life time?","a":"4","b":"12","c":"20","d":"16","hint":"","correct":"b"},{"question":"Under which of the following circumstances will insulin be secreted?","a":"The blood sugar level in the liver is low.","b":"The blood sugar level in the hepatic portal vein is low.","c":"The blood sugar level in the islets of Langerhans is high.","d":"The glycogen level in the skeletal muscle is high.","hint":"","correct":"c"},{"question":"Which one of the given option represents lophodont?","a":"Incisors and canines","b":"Canines and premolars","c":"Premolars and molars","d":"Incisors and premolars","hint":"","correct":"c"},{"question":"What is common among amylase, renin and trypsin?","a":"All are proteins.","b":"All are proteolytic enzymes.","c":"Produced in stomach.","d":"Act at pH lower than 7.","hint":"","correct":"a"},{"question":"Valves of Kerckring (also called plicae circulares or valvulae conniventes) occur in:","a":"between right auricle and right ventricle.","b":"left auricle and left ventricle.","c":"stomach and duodenum.","d":"intestine.","hint":"","correct":"d"},{"question":"In pancreatic juice, which of the followings are secreted in inactive form as proenzymes?","a":"Trypsin, chymotrypsin, & Critical carboxypeptidases","b":"Pepsin, trypsin and chymotrypsin","c":"Trypsin and chymotrypsin only","d":"Trypsin only","hint":"","correct":"a"},{"question":"If the bile-pancreatic duct is blocked then which of the following will not be affected?","a":"Digestion of proteins","b":"Emulsification of fats","c":"Level of blood glucose","d":"Digestion of starch","hint":"","correct":"c"},{"question":"Dental formula shows type and number of teeth in: ","a":"Upper jaw","b":"Lower jaw","c":"Both jaws","d":"One half of both jaws","hint":"","correct":"d"},{"question":"Bow legged condition in children is due to deficiency of vitamin:","a":"D","b":"A","c":"K","d":"c","hint":"","correct":"d"},{"question":"In ruminants, bacterial  action occurs in:","a":"Reticulum","b":"Omasum","c":"Abomasum","d":"Rumen","hint":"","correct":"d"},{"question":"Riboflavin deficiency  causes which disease?","a":"Scurvy","b":"Pellagra","c":"Beriberi","d":"Cheilosis","hint":"","correct":"d"},{"question":"Ampulla of Vater is guarded by:","a":"Sphincter of Oddi","b":"Pyloric sphincter","c":"Cardiac sphincter","d":"Anal sphincter","hint":"","correct":"a"},{"question":"Alimentary canal of herbivores Differ from carnivores having: ","a":"Short alimentary canal","b":"Long alimentary canal","c":"Wide alimentary canal","d":"Thin alimentary canal","hint":"","correct":"b"},{"question":"Mental retardation in children suffering from galactosemia can be avoided by:","a":"giving them more milk.","b":"giving them milk free diet.","c":"giving them milk fortified with vitamin.","d":"giving them more proteinaceous diet.","hint":"","correct":"b"},{"question":"Excessive simulation of vagus nerve in humans may lead to:","a":"Hoarse voice","b":"Peptic ulcers","c":"Efficient digestion of proteins","d":"Irregular contractions of diaphragm","hint":"","correct":"b"},{"question":"A dental disease characterised by mottling of teeth due to ingredient in drinking water, namely:","a":"Fluorine","b":"Chlorine","c":"Boron","d":"Mercury","hint":"","correct":"a"},{"question":"Gaucher's disease is related to:","a":"Abnormal fat metabolism","b":"Vitamin deficiency","c":"Abnormal protein metabolism","d":"Disturbed carbohydrate metabolism","hint":"","correct":"a"},{"question":"Colostomy is the removal of large parts of the colon. The principal effect of a colostomy is:","a":"Diarrhoea","b":"Constipation","c":"Increased loss of bile pigments","d":"Kwashiorkor and marasmus","hint":"","correct":"a"},{"question":"Which of the following statement is true?","a":"Pepsin cannot digest casein.","b":"Trypsin can digest collagen.","c":"Pepsin cannot digest collagen.","d":"Chymotrypsin can digest casein.","hint":"","correct":"d"},{"question":"Sphincter of Oddi controls the flow of digestive juice by guarding which duct?","a":"1","b":"2","c":"3","d":"4","hint":"","correct":"c"}]